Elsadek Elnimeiry

Cell: 507-398-3095

Email: elsadekelnimeriy@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Excellent IT professional, eager to learn more and grow my career in the field. I bring 10+ years' experience in providing IT support for both software and hardware. Highly skilled in maintaining, analyzing, troubleshooting, and repairing computers/laptops, hardware, software, and peripherals. My personal areas of strength are:

- Documenting and upgrading hardware and software systems
- Creating user accounts including user rights, security, and groups creation
- Outstanding customer service and communication skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Active Directory
- Citrix
- Windows Firewalls support
- Jira/Atlassian
- Cherwell
- SSL Certificate knowledge
- VPN
- Incident Management
- Experience with Java
- Knowledge in SQL

- Group policy
- Cisco phone
- Data backup, upgrades, and retrieval
- Azure Active Directory
- Intune
- Jamf
- Powershell/Scripting
- Zoom

EDUCATION:

Saint Mary's University - Minneapolis, Minnesota

• Bachelor of Science: Informational Technology

January 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

EverCommerce Inc. 04/2017 to Present

IT Administrator

- Interact with the help desk and other teams to assist in troubleshooting, identify root cause, and provide technical support when needed
- Image Desktop and laptop computers for new employees
- Manage physical and virtual servers, including backup and restore
- Support Windows and office licensing
- Device requirements for new IT initiatives and implement and manage solutions that meet these requirements.
- Manage vendors, including MSP, cloud services providers, IT equipment supplier, and software providers.
- Maintain essential IT operations, including operating systems, security tools, applications, servers, email systems, laptops, desktops, software, and hardware
- Experience in project management, application design and integration, and cloud computing (specifically Microsoft Azure)

Service Desk Analyst

- Field incoming technology requests from firm personnel via email inbox and call queue
- Effectively communicate both verbally and electronically within virtual Service Desk team environment
- Administering Microsoft Active Directory
- Multitask and prioritize time-sensitive tasks in a dynamic high-pressure environment
- Able to troubleshoot and resolve complex issues
- Saw issues through end-to-end with high customer satisfaction (per customer surveys)
- Oversaw and ran the Service Desk's VIP support process single-handedly

ECMC - Oakdale, Minnesota

08/2012 to 08/2015

Service Desk Technician

- Act as first point of contact for IT needs. Track issues and take ownership of problems.
- Escalate issues and involve experts wherever required to resolve issues as quickly as possible.
- Gathers information about problems from the end-user by asking clarifying questions, presenting options and/or solutions and determining the level of complexity.
- Recognizes and identifies potential areas where existing policies and procedures require change, or where new ones need to be developed.
- Assist in maintaining internal and external facing knowledge base
- Utilizes ticketing system; accurately, quickly, and efficiently recording all interactions with customers while consistently meeting established Service Desk Key Performance Indicators.
- Assisted in planning and executing two operating system upgrades across the entire network.
- Investigates and implements ways of reducing calls to the Service Desk.
- Helps with unscheduled system outages or with unresolved issues to ensure timely updates to customers.
- Consulting with other vendors to identify best approaches to resolving complex issues.

Apple, Inc. – Minneapolis, Minnesota

01/2009 to 08/2012

Service Desk Technician

- Provided technical support for customers related to the installation, troubleshooting and integration of iOS
- Software products and supporting technologies
- Provided direct assistance to customers as an escalation and collaborative problem-solving point for more complex support cases
- Implemented company policies, technical procedures and standards for preserving the integrity and security of data, reports and access
- Utilized available resources to independently resolve support issues
- Created and maintained internal and external documentation related to technical topic specialty

IBM – Rochester, Minnesota

01/2004 to 05/2008

Desktop Support Technician

- Set up hardware and install and configure software and drivers
- Maintain and repair technological equipment (e.g. routers) or peripheral devices
- Install well-functioning LAN/WAN and other networks and manage components (servers, IPs etc.)
- Manage security options and software in computers and networks to maintain privacy and protection from attacks
- Perform regular upgrades to ensure systems remain updated
- Troubleshoot system failures or bugs and provide solutions to restore functionality

ADDITIONAL CAPABILITIES

Self-starter with ability to work with minimum supervision

- Outstanding customer service and communication skills
- Exceptional logic and problem-solving acumen
- Group-effort and teamwork focused
- Profound ability to follow instructions and finish work assignments in a timely manner